[Music]
for decades japan has had the longest
life expectancy in the world while
spending just a fraction on healthcare
compared to other high-income countries
this longevity has been attributed in
part to japanese dietary patterns which
are thought to have contributed to their
comparatively low rates of coronary
artery disease
japan has historically had amongst the
lowest rates of colon cancer breast
cancer ovarian cancer prostate cancer
bladder and blood cancers
japan however has among the highest
rates of stomach cancer yes japanese men
may have had seven times less prostate
cancer than americans but got six times
more stomach cancer is there some
achilles heel in the japanese diet
one of the first theories proposed in
the 1970s was that it was the talc used
to polish white rice to give it a glossy
sheen
that was the case with ovarian cancer
which led to billions in damages against
johnson and johnson's baby powder as i
detailed in a previous video but that
did not appear to be the case with
stomach cancer is it just genetics no
studies on japanese migrants show that
as they and their children westernize
their diets and lifestyles their stomach
cancer rates drop accordingly
well the most well-established risk
factor for stomach cancer is h pylori a
bacteria that infects the lining of the
stomach and causes the chronic
inflammation that can lead to cancer
h pylori infection is considered a group
1 carcinogen indicating our highest
level of certainty that it indeed causes
cancer
korea and japan have the highest rates
of stomach cancer and among the highest
incidence of h pylori infection
case closed then right the mystery
seemed to have been solved
but then
came the african enigma
countries such as nigeria had even more
h pylori but only a fraction of japan's
stomach cancer rates
then came the indian enigma h pylori is
twice as prevalent in india than japan
yet indians get 10 times less stomach
cancer obviously h pylori alone can't
explain japan's epidemic
though most cases of stomach cancer are
thought caused by h pylori most people
with h pylori don't get cancer
h pylori is one of the most common human
infections it's been estimated that half
of the world's adult population is
infected with h pylori yet half of us
don't get stomach cancer
there must be some kind of co-factor in
countries like korea and japan that
explains their elevated cancer rates
the inflammation caused by h pylori may
just set the stage for cancer formation
increasing the susceptibility of the
stomach landing to dietary carcinogens
but what's so carcinogenic about korean
and japanese diets
studies that have compared the dietary
components of different asian
populations with similar h pylori rates
but dramatically different stomach
cancer rates have suggested preserved
salted foods both fish and vegetables as
the culprits
fresh vegetables and fruits on the other
hand were associated with an 85
reduction in stomach cancer odds whereas
consumption of fresh fish doesn't appear
associated with stomach cancer either
way
a review of 60 studies found that the
assumption of pickled foods was
associated with significantly higher
rates of stomach cancer though more so
in korea than japan perhaps because per
capita korean consumption of salt
fermented vegetables like kimchi is five
day times greater
you can't know for sure though
until you
put it to the test
pickled vegetable extracts can cause dna
damage in cells in a petri dish but what
about in people
researchers in vancouver fed people 30
ounces of fukushimsuke assorted
vegetables pickled and soy sauce or
pickled cucumbers over a three-day
period biopsies taken from their stomach
lining before the experiments started
were normal as were the biopsies taken
after eating fresh carrots or cucumbers
but after just a few days of consuming
pickled vegetables moderate to severe
tissue abnormalities were found
suggestive of stomach irritation
the consumption of non-fermented soy
foods such as tofu edamame and soy milk
is linked to a lower risk of stomach
cancer in japan whereas no association
was found with
fermented soy foods even highly salted
miso
the protection afforded by soy foods was
attributed to the anti-inflammatory and
antioxidant effects of the isoflavone
compounds in soybeans
salt itself isn't considered a direct
carcinogen but it may damage the stomach
lining thin the protective mucous layer
enhance h pylori colonization enhance
the penetration of carcinogens and
enhance the formation of carcinogens
even moderately high salt intake is
associated with significantly increased
risk of stomach cancer though in japan
this effect may be limited to those
already suffering from h pylori induced
inflammation
h pylori is typically treated with a
cocktail of multiple antibiotics is
there any way to eradicate it naturally
through diet
we'll find out
next
[Music]
you